Hello friends, welcome to Insurance Technical.
Here you get
only insurance information
from insurance professionals, that too
in very simple language. Today's
topic of discussion is Max Bupa's health insurance
policy named Relax. Friends,
in my view, Max Bupa is a company
that keeps bringing innovative products and coverage
to the market, and Max Bupa Ta Resood is
a step in this direction. The
most special thing about this policy is the re-statement of Swami
Shore, under which Swami Shore statements are made for love affairs and
even for illness.
But one thing to keep in
mind is that there will be
no re-statement for the same hospitalization, nor is there any Swami Shore restatement for the
same hospitalization in any policy.
Although there are
many health insurance products in the market
that
provide the option of re-insurance, but
most of them either do
not cover other hospitalizations related to that illness, or are
not for that person, or re-instate a maximum of
100 percent of the sum insured.
However, in this policy,
you can make unlimited re-insurances.  You
can do this for a love affair, or even
for other hospitalizations related to meeting the same person. The
next special feature of this policy is the
booster benefit, which is linked to a no-claim
bonus. After taking this policy, if you do
n't claim for one year, your sum assured
increases by 50%, and if you do
n't clear it in the second year, it increases by another 50%. This
means that after not claiming for two consecutive years,
your sum assured doubles.
After the sum assured doubles, it
stops increasing. The next special feature of this policy
is the day-1 health checkup coverage, which is
₹500 per one lakh sum assured.
If you take a sum assured of ₹5 lakh,
you will get ₹2,500 per year for health checkups. The
next special feature is that the policy is
also available for long-term use. You can
take this policy for one year, two years, or even up to three years. A
basic feature of any mediclaim policy is the
room rent limit.  There is
no room rent limit in this policy.
You can receive treatment
in a room or suite of the category you wish to avail of. The
next
important aspect of Happy End's post-
hospitalization policy is that
hospitalization is covered for 30 days and
post-hospitalization is covered for 180 days.
If you want complete information on pre- and post-hospitalization,
I have
made a video on it. You should definitely watch it.
Generally, pre- and post-
graduation coverage is for 30 days and 7 days, respectively.
Some policies
also cover post-hospitalization for up to 90 days,
but this policy covers up to 120 days.
This policy covers the entire hospitalization period of the organ donor, up
to the limit, except at the time of the policy. Under this policy,
pre-existing insurance coverage
is extended after the policy expires, meaning that
hospitalization related to the illness that was present at the time of policy purchase is covered after 3 years.
This policy also includes air ambulance
coverage, with a maximum limit of
Rs 1.5 lakh. All other required coverages are covered in
this policy.  The policy includes
coverage for alternative treatment, modern
treatment, second medical opinion,
coverage for domiciliary treatment and home
treatment like chemotherapy and
dialysis. Under this policy, you
get the facility of life-long removal. By taking this
policy, you can
save up to 30% on your renewal premium.
You also get tax benefit on STDs under this policy. You
can take a premium of Rs 3 lakh to Rs 1 crore under this policy.
This policy
is available for people between 18 and 65 years of age and
you can remove this policy for life time. Now let's talk about the
premium. If we look at the premium of Rs 5 lakh, if an
individual wants to take this policy, that is, it will have
coverage for one person, then if a
25-year-old person takes a policy of Rs 5 lakh, then
his premium will be
Rs 7697 per year. The premium for a 45-year-old
person will be Rs 9600 and Rs 1000 per year. The
premium for a 65-year-old person will be Rs 1000 per year.  It will be
Rs. 3949 per year. If we talk about two people, if
husband and wife
want to take the policy and the husband is 108 years old
and the wife is 25 years old, then the
premium for both of them will be Rs. 11400.90. If I
talk about family floater, then
on the road near 5 lakhs, if the father has a daughter of two
years and has married 38 years ago, he has his first child himself
and the second child is five years old, then the
annual premium of Venus, the lord of 5 lakhs, will be Rs.
20200.32. From this you
can estimate your premium. If you find the
premium of this policy to be high, then if you
want to take a good policy at a lower premium, then you can see SBI's Arogya Plus
policy. I have
made a video on it.
You can also watch this video by pressing the i button right now or
you will get the option at the end of this video
and I have also given it in the description of this video.
Friends, let
me make it clear to you that I have
made this for information purpose so that
people who  Those who have taken this policy or want to take it,
they should get information about this policy. I
hope the information was useful, so please
encourage me by liking this video. If you have
not yet subscribed to this channel, then do so
and stay with us
for information about insurance from insurance professionals. If you
have any question or advice, then
write it in the comment box and finally, thank you very much for taking out your valuable
time and watching this video.